<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andre S. Giron</title>
    <description>Made with &lt;3 in Atlanta, GA</description>
    <link>http://andregiron.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://andregiron.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 13:23:13 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 13:23:13 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Santa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Santa,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I’m a big kid already, but people keep asking me what I want for Christmas this year. I would love for you to pass this letter onto them.
As of right now I am 27 years old and will turn 28 by the time Christmas happens in 2020. Before you try to deliver my presents to Atlanta this year, I wanted to remind you that I’ve moved to San Francisco this year.
It’s really nice out here as you may know already! Unfortunately due to the pandemic going on right now I cannot leave out milk and cookies for you as usual. Don’t worry though, I’ll leave out a nice goodie bag for you with individually wrapped treats and some hand sanitizer. Now that wwe got everything out of the way, let’s talk about what I would like for Christmas this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apples-new-mac-mini&quot;&gt;Apple’s New Mac Mini&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, Apple did something really special and released a new Mac Mini featuring a processor that Apple designed themselves. It’s really fast, and really new so not a lot of software runs on it yet, but don’t worry Santa, if you get me one, I’ll help out and help bring more software to these new machines. If you don’t know which model to get me, it’s pretty easy. I’d like the one with the most RAM and storage you can get me. I’m not picky though, so you can get me whatever model yoru elves can build this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-clothes&quot;&gt;New Clothes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know Santa! This is crazy! All those years when hyou got me clothes, and I wasn’t so excited … well this year I’d love some new clothes and really want to start dressing like an adult. Some nice dress shirts would be awesome. I’d also like some new pairs of jeans and Chinos. My jeans have broken zippers and holes, so please get me new clothes over that silly Mac Mini. I’m not really sure what size clothes to get me this year, so you might want to get me a gift card or something. Due to the quarantine I may be a little more jolly this year just like you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;kitchen-ware&quot;&gt;Kitchen Ware&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to also maybe get some better kitchen supplies as well Santa. I know this is a lot to ask for, and you are busy with getting toys for all the kids, but I’m sure Mrs. Claus could help youu figure out some nice things for my kitchen. I’d really like a nice cutting board and maybe a nice knife for cutting vegetables. A nice new frying pan or cast iron pan would be awesome as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this letter is a little long, but I just wanted to let you know what was on my mind this Christmas. Please take care of the children first this year Santa. THey need all the gifts, love and Christmas cheer they can get. You might not notice it on the North Pole, but it’s been a crazy year this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andre&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://andregiron.me/christmas/2020/12/06/dear-santa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andregiron.me/christmas/2020/12/06/dear-santa.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>christmas</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Consistently Create</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing sucks. I have all these great ideas in my head, but can never seem to get them out on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally do sit down to write, I choke and freeze up on the keyboard, or forget how to use a pen entirely.
I’ve been spending a lot of time thinking about this, and why the creative process can be a little tough for me.
As a software developer, I actually do a ton of creative type work, so getting into the flow and slinging lots of code and
eventually putting together a kickass product is nothing new to me. So why is writing so hard?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is actually pretty simple. I code every day all day. Yet I don’t write every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between my coding and writing is just consistency. I’ve invested thousands of hours to hone in my craft as a programmer, yet I cannot say the same about writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to starting to write more regularly and consistently creating. I hope that you can join me on this journey as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://andregiron.me/writing/creativity/2019/06/08/consistently-create.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andregiron.me/writing/creativity/2019/06/08/consistently-create.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
        <category>creativity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Self</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear self,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to another great year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past year has been pretty great. I graduated from college, got a job,
and I am well underway in my career. I kicked ass and took names. If you saw all
 of the awesome stuff I have accomplished this year, you’d think that I couldn’t ask for a better life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I still find fault in lots of things around me. I long for something more.
I cannot tell you what, but I had bigger plans in mind. I’m sure I’m not alone
in this. Surely the man upstairs had something bigger planned for me than slinging
Javascript code for the rest of my life. But here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As imperfect and insecure as I feel today, I continue to go about
my life always seeking to become a better person. What’s crazy is that one of the
most applicable pieces of life advice I have ever received comes from high school baseball.
On the back of our shirts was the phrase “Be Better”. Two words that I never
thought much of at the time because well, I never thought much of anything during high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my quest to become the best I can be, I have spent a lot of time finding ways
to better organize my life. I have also devoted countless hours to becoming great at what I do.
Over time, I have learned one thing and one thing only. Nothing is free.
Learning any skill takes time. As a programmer, I always hoped that there was some
awesome hack that I could do for life to just suddenly become great. If you find it,
send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading countless self improvement books, the only one piece of advice has really mattered
came from a post on the CS Career Questions subreddit. In typical millenial fashion, OP
(original poster, for you non redditors) was complaining about his struggle to find a job.
He tried so hard to find that job! He had worked so hard and had gone though so many interviews. But the audience wasn’t having it. One of the elders chimes in with what I still consider to be one of the best responses to a sob story like OP’s:
“You gotta hustle, son.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately, I closed my laptop and thought about that profound statement for a while.
So much time wasted learning how to be great only to find that there is no trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I know that there’s a lot of stuff that I can do to improve my career
and myself. This coming year, what I want to focus on is pretty simple: putting myself
out there. I know that in the past I’ve been shy and just haven’t been taking as many
shots in life as I should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will I start taking more shots? Well, I can certainly start by publishing the other blog posts
that I have written and never got around to publishing because I was kinda scared about
what other people would think. I have about a dozen or so blog posts that I have written over the
year that have yet to see the light of day. Another thing that I can do is actually finish
a damn side project for once. I am great at starting things, but I need to finish them. By the end of the
year, I would really love to get an Android app on the market. If I don’t have one there by then, please
write to me and tell me that I need to ship an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, besides programming, I want to focus on not holding anything back because I feel worried about it.
Lots of great opportunities were missed this year that I will never get back. Oh well, you live and you learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am proud to celebrate my 23rd birthday.
Happy birthday self. Stop worrying. Things will be okay. I love you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to another great year,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Andre&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Let’s keep OP’s sexuality out of this conversation. It’s 2015!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://andregiron.me/birthday/life/2015/12/11/23-dear-self.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andregiron.me/birthday/life/2015/12/11/23-dear-self.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>birthday</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
