<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andre S. Giron</title>
    <description>Made with &lt;3 in Atlanta, GA</description>
    <link>http://andregiron.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://andregiron.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 12:28:28 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 12:28:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Web Publishing Sucks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few months I’ve been working a lot with scaling a WordPress blog. Let me first say that I have really enjoyed working with WordPress, and it’s certainly a user friendly way to post content to the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This problem has been keeping me up at night, and I’m afraid that there’s not a great solution on the market just yet. It’s almost 2020, and I thought that we’d be here by now. But then I remembered that we were promised flying cars, and I’ve yet to see any of those on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something really exciting about the problem space of web publishing to me. There certainly is no lack of content on the internet, but if I were to bet on anything, I’d bet on the fact that companies are going to be more reliant on content marketing than ever in the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that reliance on content marketing comes a need for companies to write more content than ever, shoot short films, put out a weekly podcast and manage a whole host of social media channels. This sounds like a full time job, and it certainly is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been putting in full time hours just managing a blog working on dealing with scaling issues around WordPress. This involves many things. Managing where images are stored, putting content behind a CDN, installing and keeping a myriad of plugins up to date, keeping backups, and even setting up staging environments to try out changes before shipping to production. That’s a lot! And it’s only a small part of the many things that a content team needs to stay on top of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like my job and enjoy working with WordPress, but I feel like surely there are better ways to handle things like content management. Naturally, I began to look for alternatives to WordPreass. There are many alternatives, yet most of them were quite pricey and migrating to a new CMS seems like quite the undertaking. So for now, I feel locked into WordPress, or at least until I can engineer something better for my day to day usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I rule out WordPress or any alternatives, let’s talk about my needs (In no particular order):
-Store images in Azure Storage or S3. We have a lot of media that we work with and will need to offload it somewhere. Azure Storage and S3 do a fantastic job at this.
-Easy to create staging environments. To have fast feedback loops, I need to be able to spin up and tear down a staging environment with ease and have all our content accessible from the staging environment.
-Super fast load times. Since content marketing is the goal of the site I work on, we need to have good scores on tests like PageSpeed Insights to rank well in the search engines. I’d like to have near perfect scores for mobile and for desktop versions of the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice to haves:
-Content planning functionality- It would be awesome for the content team to have a content calendar built into whatever system that they are using so that they can understand what content goes out to our blog, social media, etc.
-Editing and Commenting- We use Google Docs to handle the drafting of content and rely on comments and collaborative editing to get the job done. With today’s modern web applications, a collaborative editing experience is almost to be expected. So is things like auto saving, and keeping a copy in localStorage should the user experience an intermittent internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other stuff that I really want:
-Static by default. Static sites are really, really fast. I’d love a system that puts all my content into a static site by the time the build process is completed. Bonus points for supporting things like incremental builds. When I change one post out of 10,000, I don’t really want to have to rebuild the entire website if only the content of a post changed.
-Local and remote push and pull- I’d love an environment where people can log into a web interface and write content that eventually gets saved to a database. I’d also like the ability to be a developer and sync my local workstation with the latest content that has been posted online. Having something like this would make my life as a developer supporting a content team about 10x easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, that’s a lot already, but I have many more things that I would like to see out of a web publishing system.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andregiron.me/content/creation/creativity/wordpress/2019/06/08/web-publishing-sucks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andregiron.me/content/creation/creativity/wordpress/2019/06/08/web-publishing-sucks.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>content</category>
        
        <category>creation</category>
        
        <category>creativity</category>
        
        <category>wordpress</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Consistently Create</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing sucks. I have all these great ideas in my head, but can never seem to get them out on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally do sit down to write, I choke and freeze up on the keyboard, or forget how to use a pen entirely.
I’ve been spending a lot of time thinking about this, and why the creative process can be a little tough for me.
As a software developer, I actually do a ton of creative type work, so getting into the flow and slinging lots of code and
eventually putting together a kickass product is nothing new to me. So why is writing so hard?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is actually pretty simple. I code every day all day. Yet I don’t write every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between my coding and writing is just consistency. I’ve invested thousands of hours to hone in my craft as a programmer, yet I cannot say the same about writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to starting to write more regularly and consistently creating. I hope that you can join me on this journey as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andregiron.me/writing/creativity/2019/06/08/consistently-create.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andregiron.me/writing/creativity/2019/06/08/consistently-create.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
        <category>creativity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Self</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear self,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to another great year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past year has been pretty great. I graduated from college, got a job,
and I am well underway in my career. I kicked ass and took names. If you saw all
 of the awesome stuff I have accomplished this year, you’d think that I couldn’t ask for a better life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I still find fault in lots of things around me. I long for something more.
I cannot tell you what, but I had bigger plans in mind. I’m sure I’m not alone
in this. Surely the man upstairs had something bigger planned for me than slinging
Javascript code for the rest of my life. But here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As imperfect and insecure as I feel today, I continue to go about
my life always seeking to become a better person. What’s crazy is that one of the
most applicable pieces of life advice I have ever received comes from high school baseball.
On the back of our shirts was the phrase “Be Better”. Two words that I never
thought much of at the time because well, I never thought much of anything during high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my quest to become the best I can be, I have spent a lot of time finding ways
to better organize my life. I have also devoted countless hours to becoming great at what I do.
Over time, I have learned one thing and one thing only. Nothing is free.
Learning any skill takes time. As a programmer, I always hoped that there was some
awesome hack that I could do for life to just suddenly become great. If you find it,
send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading countless self improvement books, the only one piece of advice has really mattered
came from a post on the CS Career Questions subreddit. In typical millenial fashion, OP
(original poster, for you non redditors) was complaining about his struggle to find a job.
He tried so hard to find that job! He had worked so hard and had gone though so many interviews. But the audience wasn’t having it. One of the elders chimes in with what I still consider to be one of the best responses to a sob story like OP’s:
“You gotta hustle, son.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately, I closed my laptop and thought about that profound statement for a while.
So much time wasted learning how to be great only to find that there is no trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I know that there’s a lot of stuff that I can do to improve my career
and myself. This coming year, what I want to focus on is pretty simple: putting myself
out there. I know that in the past I’ve been shy and just haven’t been taking as many
shots in life as I should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will I start taking more shots? Well, I can certainly start by publishing the other blog posts
that I have written and never got around to publishing because I was kinda scared about
what other people would think. I have about a dozen or so blog posts that I have written over the
year that have yet to see the light of day. Another thing that I can do is actually finish
a damn side project for once. I am great at starting things, but I need to finish them. By the end of the
year, I would really love to get an Android app on the market. If I don’t have one there by then, please
write to me and tell me that I need to ship an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, besides programming, I want to focus on not holding anything back because I feel worried about it.
Lots of great opportunities were missed this year that I will never get back. Oh well, you live and you learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am proud to celebrate my 23rd birthday.
Happy birthday self. Stop worrying. Things will be okay. I love you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to another great year,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Andre&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Let’s keep OP’s sexuality out of this conversation. It’s 2015!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://andregiron.me/birthday/life/2015/12/11/23-dear-self.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andregiron.me/birthday/life/2015/12/11/23-dear-self.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>birthday</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
