<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andre S. Giron</title>
    <description>Made with &lt;3 in San Francisco, CA</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4001/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4001/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 17:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Life Updates (/now)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I have posted an update on my life here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, there have been some exciting changes in my life!
This post will likely become the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/now&lt;/code&gt; page of my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;heres-what-im-currently-up-to&quot;&gt;Here’s what I’m currently up to:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moved from Atlanta to San Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spent quarantine in San Francisco. I know! Perfect timing!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started a new job at withjoy.com I’ve joined the awesome team at withjoy.com and now work on the growth team.
My team is responsible for the withjoy.com website before you log into the app and has built quite an awesome website if I do say so myself. Check it out and let me know what you think!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrated my 1 year anniversary at withjoy.com
I can’t believe it’s been a year already, but I’ve been working a year at Joy as a full time employee. Prior to being a full time employee at Joy, I worked with the team at Joy for about six months as a contractor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;other-fun-stuff&quot;&gt;Other fun stuff:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right before moving to San Francisco, I got really into fishkeeping.
I had a reef tank (Red Sea Reefer 170), and had a really awesome coral reef at home. Unfortunately I had to tear down my tank to move across the country. It’s still in storage in Atlanta, and will be put to use as soon as I can do so out here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;computers&quot;&gt;Computers:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve got a lot of them. Since I work in tech, they bring a lot of value to my life and I’m always happy to purchase a nice machine for myself. I’m currently writing this piece on my new M1 Macbook, which is amazing. More on the laptop later, but I’m sure you’ve probably seen a ton of awesome blog posts about it by now. If you can get your hands on one, get one! They rock.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Current hardware inventory consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2020 Apple M1 Macbook Pro
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;16GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;512 GB SSD&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This thing flies and stays cool as the other side of the pillow when in use. I can actually use it on my lap unlike my 2019 Macbook Pro. I only wish it had more USBC ports on it.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2019 Macbook Pro
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;32GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;512 GB SSD&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Intel i9 chip&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This machine was provided by my employer and it’s an awesome machine. Has a lot of power, and has put up with 40+ hours of use every week no problem. This thing handles Figma, several terminals compiling code, Zoom calls all at the same time and is an all around work horse!&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2016 Macbook Pro
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;i7 chip&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;16GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;512 GB SSD&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This machine has kicked ass for many years and is now starting to show it’s age. I’ve replaced it with my M1 Macbook pro and need to find it a new home soon.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Desktop Computer
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Ryzen 1700x CPU&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;16GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;1TB SSD&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;2 4TB HDD&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;G Force GTX 1080
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;I really want a new GPU, but they’re super hard to find now!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Various other small SSDs that I use to boot into linux and what not occasionally.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Acer Predator Helios 300
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;i7 Chip&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;16GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;G Force GTX 1050&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;1TB SSD&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;1TB HDD&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;I love my Acer Predator. It’s great for gaming on the go and is a nice compomise of size and power as a laptop. Originally I bought this to be used as a Streaming PC, but I’ve found that it does just fine on it’s own as a gaming computer and has been used in several get togethers when gaming at friends’ houses.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now, I’ll try to keep this page and my /now page up to date should my life or hardware situation change!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4001/now/2021/03/26/life-updates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4001/now/2021/03/26/life-updates.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>now</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Codespaces</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;GitHub Codespaces are finally out of beta and I’m super excited to be able to try them out in my day to day workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, being able to click on a repository, spin up a development environment and be able to start coding right away is pretty amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using the 13’ Macbook Pro as my daily driver for a while now and have been wanting to blog a bit about my experience with the device. Ironically, the program that I’ve struggled to run the most powers this very blog – jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until today, where I was bored on a Saturday morning during a holiday weekend that I decided to give Codespaces a try. After struggling for a while to get my Macbook to work with my blog, I was pleasantly surprised to see that Codespaces worked with one click and even included Jekyll installed by default! I’m not so sure how this happened, but I suspect it’s probably since Jekyll is a project that originated at Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, back to watching some college football! Can’t wait to post here later with some Codespaces shenanigans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4001/programming,/dev-tools/2021/03/26/codespaces.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4001/programming,/dev-tools/2021/03/26/codespaces.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>programming,</category>
        
        <category>dev-tools</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Santa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Santa,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I’m a big kid already, but people keep asking me what I want for Christmas this year. I would love for you to pass this letter onto them.
As of right now I am 27 years old and will turn 28 by the time Christmas happens in 2020. Before you try to deliver my presents to Atlanta this year, I wanted to remind you that I’ve moved to San Francisco this year.
It’s really nice out here as you may know already! Unfortunately due to the pandemic going on right now I cannot leave out milk and cookies for you as usual. Don’t worry though, I’ll leave out a nice goodie bag for you with individually wrapped treats and some hand sanitizer. Now that wwe got everything out of the way, let’s talk about what I would like for Christmas this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apples-new-mac-mini&quot;&gt;Apple’s New Mac Mini&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, Apple did something really special and released a new Mac Mini featuring a processor that Apple designed themselves. It’s really fast, and really new so not a lot of software runs on it yet, but don’t worry Santa, if you get me one, I’ll help out and help bring more software to these new machines. If you don’t know which model to get me, it’s pretty easy. I’d like the one with the most RAM and storage you can get me. I’m not picky though, so you can get me whatever model yoru elves can build this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-clothes&quot;&gt;New Clothes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know Santa! This is crazy! All those years when hyou got me clothes, and I wasn’t so excited … well this year I’d love some new clothes and really want to start dressing like an adult. Some nice dress shirts would be awesome. I’d also like some new pairs of jeans and Chinos. My jeans have broken zippers and holes, so please get me new clothes over that silly Mac Mini. I’m not really sure what size clothes to get me this year, so you might want to get me a gift card or something. Due to the quarantine I may be a little more jolly this year just like you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;kitchen-ware&quot;&gt;Kitchen Ware&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to also maybe get some better kitchen supplies as well Santa. I know this is a lot to ask for, and you are busy with getting toys for all the kids, but I’m sure Mrs. Claus could help youu figure out some nice things for my kitchen. I’d really like a nice cutting board and maybe a nice knife for cutting vegetables. A nice new frying pan or cast iron pan would be awesome as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this letter is a little long, but I just wanted to let you know what was on my mind this Christmas. Please take care of the children first this year Santa. THey need all the gifts, love and Christmas cheer they can get. You might not notice it on the North Pole, but it’s been a crazy year this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andre&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4001/christmas/2020/12/06/dear-santa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4001/christmas/2020/12/06/dear-santa.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>christmas</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Consistently Create</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing sucks. I have all these great ideas in my head, but can never seem to get them out on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally do sit down to write, I choke and freeze up on the keyboard, or forget how to use a pen entirely.
I’ve been spending a lot of time thinking about this, and why the creative process can be a little tough for me.
As a software developer, I actually do a ton of creative type work, so getting into the flow and slinging lots of code and
eventually putting together a kickass product is nothing new to me. So why is writing so hard?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is actually pretty simple. I code every day all day. Yet I don’t write every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between my coding and writing is just consistency. I’ve invested thousands of hours to hone in my craft as a programmer, yet I cannot say the same about writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to starting to write more regularly and consistently creating. I hope that you can join me on this journey as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4001/writing/creativity/2019/06/08/consistently-create.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4001/writing/creativity/2019/06/08/consistently-create.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
        <category>creativity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Self</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear self,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to another great year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past year has been pretty great. I graduated from college, got a job,
and I am well underway in my career. I kicked ass and took names. If you saw all
 of the awesome stuff I have accomplished this year, you’d think that I couldn’t ask for a better life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I still find fault in lots of things around me. I long for something more.
I cannot tell you what, but I had bigger plans in mind. I’m sure I’m not alone
in this. Surely the man upstairs had something bigger planned for me than slinging
Javascript code for the rest of my life. But here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As imperfect and insecure as I feel today, I continue to go about
my life always seeking to become a better person. What’s crazy is that one of the
most applicable pieces of life advice I have ever received comes from high school baseball.
On the back of our shirts was the phrase “Be Better”. Two words that I never
thought much of at the time because well, I never thought much of anything during high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my quest to become the best I can be, I have spent a lot of time finding ways
to better organize my life. I have also devoted countless hours to becoming great at what I do.
Over time, I have learned one thing and one thing only. Nothing is free.
Learning any skill takes time. As a programmer, I always hoped that there was some
awesome hack that I could do for life to just suddenly become great. If you find it,
send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading countless self improvement books, the only one piece of advice has really mattered
came from a post on the CS Career Questions subreddit. In typical millenial fashion, OP
(original poster, for you non redditors) was complaining about his struggle to find a job.
He tried so hard to find that job! He had worked so hard and had gone though so many interviews. But the audience wasn’t having it. One of the elders chimes in with what I still consider to be one of the best responses to a sob story like OP’s:
“You gotta hustle, son.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately, I closed my laptop and thought about that profound statement for a while.
So much time wasted learning how to be great only to find that there is no trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I know that there’s a lot of stuff that I can do to improve my career
and myself. This coming year, what I want to focus on is pretty simple: putting myself
out there. I know that in the past I’ve been shy and just haven’t been taking as many
shots in life as I should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will I start taking more shots? Well, I can certainly start by publishing the other blog posts
that I have written and never got around to publishing because I was kinda scared about
what other people would think. I have about a dozen or so blog posts that I have written over the
year that have yet to see the light of day. Another thing that I can do is actually finish
a damn side project for once. I am great at starting things, but I need to finish them. By the end of the
year, I would really love to get an Android app on the market. If I don’t have one there by then, please
write to me and tell me that I need to ship an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, besides programming, I want to focus on not holding anything back because I feel worried about it.
Lots of great opportunities were missed this year that I will never get back. Oh well, you live and you learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am proud to celebrate my 23rd birthday.
Happy birthday self. Stop worrying. Things will be okay. I love you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to another great year,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Andre&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Let’s keep OP’s sexuality out of this conversation. It’s 2015!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4001/birthday/life/2015/12/11/23-dear-self.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4001/birthday/life/2015/12/11/23-dear-self.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>birthday</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
